this person requested Pythagorean
theorem so we start with the square then
we have another Square that's the exact
same size so these two squares are equal
to each other then I'll make a cut that
is the same size as a and I'll do the
same thing to the other Square do the
same thing to every side of that square
and the same thing to every side of this
square and then this other piece will be
B then if I make a cut right here on
both squares and pull this triangle out
this is the same triangle that's in our
notes up above so this side right here
is C this side is also C and let's bring
these down here next let's make another
cut here where this is a and this is B
and let's make a cut here where this is
C and then if we pull both of these
triangles out and bring them down there
these two sides should still be equal to
each other because we pulled the two
same triangles out of both of them now
let's make some more Cuts here here and
here and also here and here we've now
made more of these ABC triangles and we
can pull them out and bring them down
here and so out of both sides we've
pulled four of these ABC triangles so
they should both still be equal so this
square right here is an a by a square so
the area of it is a squ this square has
sides B so its area is b^ squ and this
square has side C so its area is c^ 2 we
can call this left hand side a^ 2 + b^ 2
cuz we're adding these two squares
together and that's going to be equal to
this right hand side which is c^2 how
exciting